Paul Mora

E-Mail: **☑** • Website: **☑** • Phone: +49 157 3566 9584

SUMMARY

Data Scientist and Econometrician with 3+ years experience. Focused on statistical analysis and time series forecasting models in Python. Experienced at explaining technical topics to a non-technical audience. Founder of two Start-ups, fluent in English and German, Data Science Teacher and University of Oxford Alumni.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python (incl. Numpy, Pandas, Requests, Keras, NLTK, Selenium, NoSQL), R, SQL, MATLAB
- + 30 Selected Machine Learning Projects/ Articles (+2500 monthly readers) to be found here 🗷 🖸

WORK EXPERIENCE

EY, Berlin October 2020 - Present

Technology Consultant - Data Scientist

• At EY I am part of the Data and Analytics Team, developing and implementing Data Science models and techniques for the Financial Insdustry

Oxera Consulting LLP, Berlin/London

June 2019 - September 2020

Data Scientist & Economic Consultant

At Oxera I combined econometrics and Data Science, advising companies and policymakers on analytical issues. Furthermore, I taught fellow employees Machine Learning in Python and regularly presented technical topics to Partners and the advisory board.

My latest project involved the construction of a counterfactual forecasting model for the price path of pharmaceutical drugs.

data4help, Berlin

May 2020 - Present

Co-Founder & Data Scientist

• Co-Founded a skill-based volunteering company helping non-profits to make use of their data

Data Science Retreat, Berlin

September 2019 - Present

Data Science Teacher

• Teaching Python courses and mentoring bootcamp of ten to twelve participants

STUDY42, Frankfurt

November 2018 - January 2020

Founder & Teacher

• Independently founded tutoring company, hired and managed team of eight tutors

German Central Bank, Frankfurt

August 2017 - August 2018

Data Analyst & Economist

• Predicted capital buffers of the European Insurance sector to aid macroprudential regulation

EDUCATION

University of Oxford, Oxford

2018 - 2019

Master of Science - Financial Economics - Dean's List & Distinction

Goethe University Frankfurt, Frankfurt

2014 - 2017

Bachelor of Science - Economics - Dean's List & Distinction